<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Antoine Martin</title>
    <link>https://martantoine.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Antoine Martin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 18:28:01 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://martantoine.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://martantoine.github.io/posts/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 18:28:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martantoine.github.io/posts/about/</guid>
      <description>Who am I My name is Antoine Martin (aka martantoine). Originaly from France, studies and work brought me so far to many places, namely:
 San Francisco - Bay Area, USA 🇺🇸  Master thesis then full time Robotics Engineer since March 2025   Eindhoven, Netherlands 🇳🇱  Software Engineer intern @ ASML - 2024-2025 (6 months)   Lausanne, Switzerland 🇨🇭  BSc MicroEngineering @ EPFL* - 2022 MSc Robotics @ EPFL - 2025    Area of expertise My main area of expertise is in:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quadruped Robot with Tensegrity Joints actuated via Pneumatic Artificial Muscles</title>
      <link>https://martantoine.github.io/posts/quadruped/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 18:28:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martantoine.github.io/posts/quadruped/</guid>
      <description>The design of a quadruped robot with tensegrity joints and McKibbens artificial muscles is a complex challenge, as it involves the intricate task of designing a multi-axis compliant joint integrated with compliant actuation. Analytical resolutions, simulations, and real-world measurement were necessary to solve this complex design problem. The demonstrator itself was first tested in Mujoco simulation before actually building it.
It was possible to eliminate the need for antagonistic pairs of muscles thanks to the introduction of a restoring force in every joint, hence reducing by a factor of two the number of actuators when compared with the antagonistic approach, eventually making the robot lighter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 DOFs Robotic Arm</title>
      <link>https://martantoine.github.io/posts/5dofsarm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martantoine.github.io/posts/5dofsarm/</guid>
      <description>Description  ⚠️ Warning WARNING: This post describes a project known to be of very low quality. You might experience nausea while reading it.
.. This is an old project from high-school. Back then I had no idea about how to properly engineer anything, more specifically:
 how to properly design a robot (e.g: torque balancing) concurrent motor control (everything runs in a single thread..) inverse kinematic, it is totally missing here -_-   This project is about designing and manufacturing a simple 5 DOFs robotic arm.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
